furl.net 2006-12-30

# LookSmart's Furl - Privacy Policy

Your privacy is very important to us. Furl and its parent company, LookSmart, Ltd. (referred to in this Privacy Policy as "Furl") have created this Privacy Policy in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to protecting your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the www.furl.net site (the "Site"). 

Who is collecting my information?

Furl usually collects the requested information. However, Furl has chosen select partners in order to provide certain services. In order to use certain services on the Site, it may be necessary to enter information that then goes to our partner and is not kept by Furl. 

We contract with Coremetrics, a service partner, to provide us with a data collection and reporting service for our Site. If you access the Site, Coremetrics may collect information about you on our behalf. For further information, including how to opt out of such data gathering, please see: <http://www.coremetrics.com/info_eluminate2.html>. 

Please be aware that advertisers or sites that have links on the Site may collect personally identifiable information about you once you have clicked through to their sites. This privacy statement does not cover the information practices of those sites linked to or from Furl. 

Back to top

How does Furl use my information?

Furl's primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on our service. This includes, or may include in the future, personalization services, interactive communications, online shopping, and many other types of services. In order to provide services free of charge, we will serve ads using content-targeting technologies, based on the content of your archived items. Except where required to resolve technical problems or as set forth herein, no human will review your archived items or information related to you. By knowing a little about you, Furl is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you. 

Back to top

With whom does Furl share my information?

The following describes some of the ways that your information may be disclosed. Please note that this is not a complete list. The ways your information may be disclosed will change from time to time. 

Member Name: Your member name is the one part of your member profile that always remains public. Because many Furl services are interactive and community driven, it is important for other users to know who has submitted content, ratings, and comments. 

Coremetrics: Coremetrics may store certain data that we received from visitors to Furl (which may include email addresses), so that we may access this information via their reporting service. Furl will only use information shared with Coremetrics for proprietary Furl purposes. Coremetrics does not have the right to transfer your information to any party other than LookSmart. 

Business Partners: LookSmart may disclose your personal information to our business partners in order to provide you with the services on the Site. If you have questions regarding the privacy policy or data-collection practices of one of our business partners, please contact that partner directly. 

Promotions: Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. If you request more information from a sponsor, Furl will transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. 

Special Offers: From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt-in to receive information from these third parties, Furl will share your name and email address with those parties. 

Data in the Aggregate: Furl discloses aggregated user statistics (for example, 45% of our users have visited the Site more than once this month) in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. 

Other: We also may access or disclose your personal information to a third party if we believe in good faith that the law or legal process (e.g., a subpoena or warrant) requires it, to protect the rights or property of Furl or others, to respond to claims that any content on the Service or use thereof violates the rights of third parties, to enforce our Terms of Service, or as otherwise described in this privacy policy. 

Back to top

What personally identifiable information does Furl collect?

Furl collects personal information when you register. During registration, Furl requires a unique public member identity (not necessarily your real name), private password, valid email address, first name, and last name. No other personal information is required for users to register for the Furl service. Once you register, you are no longer anonymous to Furl. Your member name and first and last name are made public to the Furl community and general public. Other registration information is not displayed publicly unless you opt for it to be displayed publicly. 

You may provide additional personal information at other times, including (but not limited to) when you create a Member Profile, provide opinions or ratings, enter a sweepstakes, contest, or promotion sponsored by Furl and/or our partners, or when you report a problem with one of our features or services. If you contact Furl we may keep a record of that correspondence. Furl also occasionally asks users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. Furl may at times also collect IP addresses and login records for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. 

We may also collect information through the use of "pixel tags" included in email messages we may send to you. Pixel tags are tiny graphic files, not visible to the human eye, that are included in HTML-encoded email messages. When such a message is opened in an HTML-capable email program, the recipient's computer will access our server to retrieve the pixel tag file, allowing us to record and store, along with the recipient's email address, the date and time the recipient viewed the email message, that the recipient's email program is capable of receiving HTML-encoded email, and other standard logging information. The pixel tag also may see or read cookies. 

Back to top

What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?

You can browse the Site without creating an account (by logging in under the username "demo" and using the password "demo"), but you will need to create an account in order to take full advantage of the Site. 

Furl may, from time to time, send you email regarding our products and services. In most cases, you will be given the opportunity to choose not to receive these messages. In some instances, emails are a necessary component of Furl's service. In addition, if you indicated upon registration that you are interested in receiving offers or information from Furl and our partners, we may occasionally send you email about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. 

By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use Furl because Furl's services require cookies in order to participate. Persistent cookies are used for the auto-login feature and session cookies are used to provide all other Furl services. Coremetrics also uses cookies as part of its service for Furl. For further information, including how to opt out of such data gathering, please see: <http://www.coremetrics.com/info_eluminate2.html>. 

Back to top

What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?

Your Furl Account Information and Member Profile are password-protected so that you and only you have access to entering and editing personal information make certain information publicly displayed. You may edit your Account Information or Member Profile using your member name and password. 

We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. Furl will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited email. Please remember to log out of your Furl account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This helps ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Furl cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. 

Back to top

What else should I know about my privacy?

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. Thus, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited and unwanted communications from other parties. 

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. 

Back to top

What is Furl's policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?

You may edit your Member Profile at any time by selecting Profile within the Site and then using your member name and password. 

Your Furl account can be deactivated and personally identifiable information deleted, but doing so will result in not being able to access Furl services outside of using the demo account. Please contact [Furl@furl.net](mailto:Furl@furl.net) if you wish to deactivate your account, clearly indicating the nature of your request. 

Back to top

What are cookies and how does Furl use them?

As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, Furl uses cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. All web pages on Furl require that you accept cookies. (See "What are my choices regarding collection, use and distribution of my information?" for more information on cookies.) 

Generally, we use cookies to: 

Remind us of who you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This cookie is set when you register or "log in" and is modified when you "log out" of our services. 

Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing Furl is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behavior. 

Assist Furl partners or affiliates to track visits to and business with their companies, and potentially to process the items in your shopping basket. This information collected by cookies is sometimes called "clickstream" or "click trail" and may also describe which pages you have seen in each merchant's store. 

Track your progress and number of entries in some of our promotions, sweepstakes, and contests. 

Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of Furl you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar to or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on Furl a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, advertisements, and promotions that you and other users will see on our Site. 

Advertising networks that serve ads onto Furl may also use their own cookies. The content of such cookies and the use of the information they contain is controlled by the third party advertising network placing them, not by Furl. 

Back to top

What about children's privacy?

Furl does not intentionally collect personal information about children under the age of 18. Children under the age of 18 may not use the Site. 

Back to top

What if Furl modifies the Privacy Policy?

Furl may need to modify the privacy policy due to updates and changes in its services. Modifications will continue to respect and safeguard your privacy. You should check this page periodically to review the latest version of the privacy policy. 

Back to top

I can't find the answer to my question about privacy.

Any other questions regarding our privacy policy should be directed to [Furl@furl.net](mailto:Furl@furl.net). 

Back to top
